licensepal.com 2018-08-20

# Privacy Policy - Web Hosting Software License Reseller - LicensePal

#### Privacy Policy

Internet user privacy and confidentiality is important to LicensePal Limited. The purpose of this policy is to explain how we use any personal information we collect about you when you use this Website ("[https://www.licensepal.com](https://www.licensepal.com/)") or interact with a member of staff. We want you to be assured that we make every effort to respect your personal and financial privacy. In addition to our Privacy Policy, your use of the services is governed by our Terms of Service, which govern in the event of any conflict with this Privacy Policy.

##### Contents

  * How does LicensePal Limited collect information from you?
  * What information do we collect about you?
  * How does LicensePal Limited use the information it collects?
  * Use of Cookies
  * Users aged 16 and under
  * Where is your data stored?
  * Security of Data
  * Access to your information and correction
  * Links to Other Sites
  * Third party data processors that LicensePal Limited use
  * Data controller
  * Changes to our Privacy Policy

##### How does LicensePal Limited collect information from you?

LicensePal Limited collects information from you when you send it to us directly by filling out forms on the Website (including any application you may make for services). We also collect information from you when you browse the Website and use the software as set out in detail below.

Once a license or service is purchased, all data described below is processed for the purpose of LicensePal Limited's legitimate interests to provide customer support, to protect the security of your account, license your software and to provide you with important information and updates.

##### What information do we collect about you?

**Information collected from the Website**

LicensePal Limited may collect information from you which may be personally identifiable such as personal names, telephone numbers, physical addresses, email addresses, credit card numbers (in the case of direct customers) and, if applicable, company name, contacts, telephone numbers, physical addresses, email addresses, credit card numbers or other payment information, as well as similar information concerning technical contacts, marketing contacts, and executive contacts within your company or organisation.

LicensePal Limited may also collect information from you such as the type of browser you use, your operating system, the screen resolution of your browser, your ISP, your IP address, which pages you view on the Website and the time and duration of your visits to the Website.

**User Communications**

If you communicate with us, we collect information relating to that communication whether it takes the form of email, testimonials or any other form of communication between you and LicensePal Limited or submitted by you to the Website (collectively, "User Communications").

##### How does LicensePal Limited use the information it collects?

LicensePal Limited processes the information visitors provide about themselves for the legal basis of legitimate interest to fulfil those visitors' requests, including the provision of licenses, provide you with customer and technical support and to communicate with you about your account and our products and services. You may update your personal Information with us or ask for removal (if no longer an active customer), otherwise we may maintain records of personal Information you disclose to us indefinitely.

LicensePal Limited may use collected information to maintain, evaluate, improve and provide our Website, to track your movements, analyse broad trends such a geographical location and by such improve our quality of service. We process your browser version to detect trends on what browsers people prefer. We may from time to time share information gathered in this way with our partners. This information is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We may retain collected information indefinitely.

We will not sell or rent this information to third parties, we may use the details you supply and upload to a third party data processor as defined below.

We may maintain records of User Communications you transmit to us indefinitely.

We may use Server Information to provide you with technical support services and to maintain and improve our services. We may also use such information to investigate unlicensed (and therefore unauthorised) uses of our software. We may maintain server information indefinitely.

##### Use of Cookies

Cookies are pieces of data stored on your hard drive concerning a current or previous web experience, such as a username/password combination used to gain access to some areas of the Website or other services. We may use a cookie to record previously established interests and preferences (via data submitted to us) so as to enhance the experience whilst using our Website.

LicensePal Limited uses the following types of cookies:

  * **Strictly Necessary** : These cookies enable our Website to function correctly and deliver the services and products you have requested.
  * **Performance & Functionality**: These cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of the Website but are non-essential to their use (for example, these cookies remember your preferences on the Website).
  * **Analytical** : These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help LicensePal Limited understand how the Website is being used. In particular LicensePal Limited use the Google Analytics cookies. If you do not wish to allow the use of Google Analytics cookies at all, Google provides an opt-out plug-in for most common Website browsers - <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

By using the Website, you accept the use of at least Strictly Necessary and Performance & Functionality cookies in accordance with this Privacy Policy. The Website will show a disclaimer asking for your consent to the use of cookies, declining this will disable the Analytical cookies only.

You may deactivate cookies in your web browser, or reject the creation of a cookie depending on your personal preferences. If you do so then our Website functionality may be compromised and certain services may not be available.

##### Users aged 16 and under

We request that individuals under 16 not provide personal data to LicensePal Limited. If we learn that we have collected personal data from a child under 16, we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.

##### Where is your data stored?

The Website and SMTP servers are hosted by AWS within the Europe/London region – for more information about where and how the servers are held please [click here](https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/).

LicensePal Limited cannot be responsible for protecting your information if you share such information in publicly available sections of the Website such as the blog comments. You should use your own judgment in disclosing this information on the Website.

##### Security of Data

Given the nature of the Internet and the fact that no security system is perfect, LicensePal Limited cannot promise that the information you provide will never be obtained by unauthorised persons. LicensePal Limited does however utilise industry-standard practices to protect your personally identifiable information from loss, misuse, alteration and destruction. Such measures include using firewalls and security layers to protect certain sensitive transmissions of information. In some areas of our Website, we require a user ID or email and password for you to access certain information.

LicensePal Limited will not disclose such passwords to third parties; however, you are responsible for maintaining the privacy and security of your password.

In the event that LicensePal Limited is purchased by another company, merges with another company or has a substantial portion of its assets purchased by another company, LicensePal Limited may share your information with that company. In such an event, we will notify you in accordance with the notice provisions of the Terms of Service.

We may share your information with third parties as permitted or required by Applicable Law, by a court order or by another judicial or governmental request. We may also disclose your information if we determine that such disclosure is necessary to protect LicensePal Limited's rights and remedies or is necessary for national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance. Such disclosures could take place in the context of an investigation or to prevent or take action against illegal activity, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of LicensePal Limited's Terms of Service, applicable EULAs or as otherwise required by Applicable Law.

##### Access to your information and correction

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will request consent (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise this right at any time by contacting us at support [@] licensepal.com.

If you reside in the European Union, you have the right under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) to request a copy for the information that we hold about you. We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information that you think is inaccurate. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please email us. If you do not live in the European Union but you believe you have a right to restriction of processing or a right to object to processing under your local laws, please contact us at support [@] licensepal.com.

##### Links to Other Sites

This Website may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that LicensePal Limited cannot be held responsible for the privacy practices of other such sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by LicensePal Limited.

##### Third party data processors that LicensePal Limited use

We use a number of third parties to process personal data on our behalf, these are:

  * **Amazon Web Services (AWS)** \- <https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/>  
Our data is stored at the AWS data centers in the UK. 
  * **Google** \- <https://www.google.com/intl/en-GB/policies/privacy/>  
This Website uses Google Analytics to track user interaction. We use this data to determine the number of people using our site, to better understand how they find and use our web pages and to see their journey through the Website. 
  * **Maxmind** \- <https://www.maxmind.com/en/privacy_policy>  
New customer data is sent to Maxmind for the purposes of fraud prevention. 
  * **SendGrid** \- <https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/>  
SendGrid may be used to send client area related emails to our customers. 

##### Data controller

The data controller of this Website is:  
LicensePal Limited (Registered UK Company: #07230912) 

See the About Us page for further contact details.

##### Changes to our Privacy Policy

LicensePal Limited reserves the right to change our privacy policy from time to time. You can determine when this policy was last updated by referring to the date at the bottom of this page. Any changes become effective upon our posting of the revised Privacy Policy.

We will provide notice to you of these changes and obtain your consent where required by applicable law. This notice will be provided by email or posting notice of the changes on our Website.

_Last updated: May 2018_
